# George Petrou

8 Deercrest Drive Holmdel, NJ, 07733 (732)-882-3687 george@gpetrou.com

Computer Engineering student with six years of programming experience and hardware developing. Looking to further knowledge and experience as an Engineering Intern in relevant areas as well as expanding upon already strong communication skills.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## APEX ENTERPRISES OF UNION INC.

Neptune City, NJ

Construction Laborer

July 2012 - Present

- Worked in teams and independently constructing/destructing municipal buildings throughout New Jersey
- Hands-on experience reading building plans and coordinating small teams to break down, simplify, and achieve subtasks
- Efficient and dedicated, able to meet deadlines in a timely manner

**PROGRAMMING** Holmdel, NJ

Programmer

June 2012 - Present

- Created an online business programming and selling various computer softwares
- Worked with clients real-time and through ticketing software solving installation difficulties and program issues
- Experienced using Git software to promote teamwork on largescale projects and track coding competition programs to keep extensive revision/history logs
- Managing open sourced software (github.com/gspetrou) with constant support and updates for upwards of three years
- Achieved over 650,000 unique downloads through online distribution platforms with certain programs reaching top 100 status out of more than 90,000 other available programs

#### **EDUCATION**

#### PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY

State College, PA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, Class of 2020

August 2016 - Present

- GPA: 3.5/4.0
- Dean's List
- Student member and local club member of IEEE
- Capital College honors program participant
- Founding father and brother of Sigma Alpha Epsilon Penn Psi-Eta Fraternity chapter
- Manager of fraternity's social media and public relations, head of design committee
- Raised over \$3000 per semester through fundraising events with proceeds donated to the Children's Miracle Network
- Bi-weekly volunteering at Habitat for Humanity building homes for disabled veterans and at Middletown Home for the Elderly
- Astronomy and Snowboarding club member

### HOLMDEL HIGH SCHOOL

Holmdel, NJ

September 2012 – June 2016

Student, Class of 2016 GPA: 3.5/4.0

- Four-year honors student
- Robotics club member

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- In-depth experience with Windows, MacOS, and Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, and CentOS)
- Experienced with MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel, Adobe Photoshop, PSpice, XCode, MS Visual Studio, Vim, and Altera Quartus Prime Pro, capable reading circuit diagrams
- Fluent in C++, Java, Lua, Python, JavaScript, web development with MySQL and other relational database experience
- Experience building computers, soldering, designing circuits, and working with integrated circuit components
- Able to understand and speak Greek